ads-securities.co.uk 2018-06-23

# Privacy Policy - ADSS

**ADS Website Privacy policy**

## **INTRODUCTION**

This Privacy Policy (the **“Policy”** ) describes how the ADS Group ( **“ADS”** ) collects, uses and shares the information you provide to us and the information we collect in the course of operating our business and our websites (regardless of where you visit it from) and informs you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

We appreciate that there is a lot of information here but we want you to be fully informed about your rights and how ADS uses your data. This Policy is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas set out below. Alternatively you can download a pdf version of the policy here. Please also use the Glossary to understand the meaning of some of the terms used in this privacy notice.

  1. **[ _IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE_ ]**
  2. **[ _THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU_ ]**
  3. **[ _HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED_ ]**
  4. **[ _HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA_ ]**
  5. **[ _DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA_ ]**
  6. **[ _INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS_ ]**
  7. **[ _DATA SECURITY_ ]**
  8. **[ _DATA RETENTION_ ]**
  9. **[ _YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS_ ]**
  10. **[ _GLOSSARY_ ]**
  11. **IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE**

**PURPOSE OF THIS POLICY**

It is important that you read this Policy together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data.

**CONTROLLER**

ADS is made up of different legal entities, details of which can be found here <https://www.adss.com/en-gb/about-ads-securities/regulation/> . This Policy is issued on behalf of the ADS Group, so when we mention ADS, “we”, “us” or “our” in this Policy, we are referring to the relevant company in ADS Group responsible for processing your data. We will let you know which entity will be the controller for your data when you purchase a product or service from us. Specifically, your data will be controlled by the ADS entity that you have approached to provide services to you in the region.

We have appointed a data protection officer (DPO) who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this Policy. If you have any questions about this Policy, including any requests to exercise your legal rights], please contact Oliver C. Hallsworth using the details set out below.

**CONTACT DETAILS**

Our full details are:

ADS SECURITIES L.L.C.

Oliver C. Hallsworth

Email address: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#94dbd7dcbad8d3d8d4f5f0e7b9e7f1f7e1e6fde0fdf1e7baf7fbf9)

Postal address: Corniche Road, PO Box 93894, Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates

Tel: +971 2 657 2300

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues ([ _www.ico.org.uk_](http://www.ico.org.uk/)). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.

**CHANGES TO THE POLICY AND YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGES**

It is likely that we will need to update this Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any significant changes.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

**THIRD-PARTY LINKS**

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

### **2\. THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:

  * **Identity Data** includes first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar identifier, marital status, title, date of birth and gender, nationality, passport and, in the case of any recruitment application, education and qualification details, your CV, photograph and any other details set out in your application.
  * **Contact Data** includes billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.
  * **Financial Data** includes bank account and payment card details.
  * **Transaction Data** includes details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us.
  * **Technical Data** includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.
  * **Profile Data** includes your username and password, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.
  * **Usage Data** includes information about how you use our website, products and services.
  * **Marketing and Communications Data** includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.

We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does **_not_** directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this Policy.

We do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we routinely collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

**IF YOU FAIL TO PROVIDE PERSONAL DATA**

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with products or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

### **3\. HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?**

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

  * **Direct interactions.** You may give us your Identity, Contact and Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
  * apply for our products or services;
  * create an account on our website;
  * subscribe to our service or publications;
  * request marketing to be sent to you;
  * enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
  * give us some feedback.
  * **Automated technologies or interactions.** As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. We may also receive Technical Data about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies. Please see our cookie policy <https://www.adss.com/en-gb/cookie-policy/> for further details.
  * **Third parties or publicly available sources.** We may also receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources.

### **4\. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation that we have to discharge.
  * Where we engage in marketing and business development activity in relation to our financial services which may include updates, marketing communications and other information that may be of interest to you.
  * Where you have applied for a position with us, to review and process your job application.
  * Use it to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights or for the purpose of legal proceedings.
  * Record and monitor your use of our websites or our other online services for our business purposes which may include analysis of usage, measurement of site performance and generation of marketing reports.
  * Use it to look into any complaints or queries you may have, and
  * Use it to prevent and respond to actual or potential fraud or other illegal activities.

We may collate, process and share any statistics based on an aggregation of information held by us provided that any individual is not identified from the resulting analysis and the collation, processing and dissemination of such information is permitted by law. Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to third party direct marketing communications to you via email or text message.

**PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE WILL USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful basis depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please [contact us](https://www.adss.com/en-gb/contact/) if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

**Purpose/Activity** | **Type of data** | **Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest**  
---|---|---  
To register you as a new customer  | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

| Performance of a contract with you   
To process and deliver your order including: 

(a) Manage payments, fees and charges

(b) Collect and recover money owed to us

| (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Financial

(d) Transaction

(e) Marketing and Communications

| (a) Performance of a contract with you 

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover debts due to us)  
  
To manage our relationship with you which will include: 

(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy

(b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey

| (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Marketing and Communications

| (a) Performance of a contract with you 

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)  
  
To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey  | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Usage

(e) Marketing and Communications

| (a) Performance of a contract with you 

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business)  
  
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)  | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

| (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise) 

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you  | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Usage

(e) Marketing and Communications

(f) Technical

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)   
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences  | (a) Technical 

(b) Usage

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)   
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you  | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

(d) Usage

(e) Profile

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)   
  
**MARKETING**

We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising. We have established the following personal data control mechanisms:

**PROMOTIONAL OFFERS FROM US**

We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or purchased products or services from us or if you provided us with your details when you entered a competition or registered for a promotion and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

**THIRD-PARTY MARKETING**

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside the ADS Group of companies for marketing purposes.

**OPTING OUT**

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by logging into the website and checking or unchecking relevant boxes to adjust your marketing preferences or by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you.

Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a product/service experience or other transactions.

**COOKIES**

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see <https://www.adss.com/en-gb/cookie-policy/>

**CHANGE OF PURPOSE**

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact Oliver C. Hallsworth.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

### **5\. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 4 above.

  * Internal Third Parties as set out in the _[Glossary](https://www.adss.com/en-gb/learn/glossary/)_.
  * External Third Parties as set out in the _Glossary_.
  * Specific third parties e.g. companies who support our website, direct marketing companies, Google, Facebook and Data Analytics companies etc.
  * Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

### **6\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

We share your personal data within the ADS Group. This will involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ).

We ensure your personal data is protected by requiring all ADS Group companies to follow the same rules when processing your personal data. These rules are called “binding corporate rules”.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see [_European Commission: Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries_](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en).
  * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see [_European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries_](https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/justice-and-fundamental-rights/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en).
  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For further details, see [_European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield_](https://ec.europa.eu/info/strategy/justice-and-fundamental-rights/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en).

Please <http://ads-securities.force.com/ukgdprdsar> if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

### **7\. DATA SECURITY**

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

### **8\. DATA RETENTION**

**HOW LONG WILL YOU USE MY PERSONAL DATA FOR?**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for a set minimum period after they cease being customers.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Your Legal Rights below for further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

### **9\. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS**

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data:

  * Request access to the personal data we hold about you.
  * Request correction of your personal data when incorrect, out of date or incomplete.
  * Request erasure of your personal data.
  * Object to processing of your personal data.
  * Request restriction of processing your personal data.
  * Request transfer of your personal data.
  * Right to withdraw consent.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact <http://ads-securities.force.com/ukgdprdsar>

**NO FEE USUALLY REQUIRED**

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly manifestly unfounded, repetitive or excessive.

**WHAT WE MAY NEED FROM YOU**

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

**TIME LIMIT TO RESPOND**

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

### **10\. GLOSSARY**

**LAWFUL BASIS**

**Legitimate Interest** means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law).

**Performance of Contract** means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.

**Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation** means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.

## **THIRD PARTIES**

**INTERNAL THIRD PARTIES**

Other companies in the ADS Group acting as joint controllers or processors and who are based in the United Arab Emirates, Singapore, Hong Kong and the United Kingdom and provide IT and system administration services and undertake management reporting.

**EXTERNAL THIRD PARTIES**

  * Service providers acting as processors based both inside and outside the EEA who provide IT and system administration services.
  * Professional advisers acting as processors or joint controllers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based both inside and outside the EEA who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
  * HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities acting as processors or joint controllers based in the United Kingdom who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances _ _

**Use of cookies by ADSS**

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with the best experience when you browse our website and also allows us to collect statistical information to enhance site functionality and performance.

If you register with us or if you continue to use our website, you are agreeing to our use of cookies.

**What is a cookie?**

A cookie is a small text file sent to your browser by a website you visit which is saved to your computer or mobile device. It enables the website to remember your actions and preferences (such as login, language and other display preferences) over a period of time, so you don’t have to keep re-entering them whenever you come back to the site or browse from one page to another.

We use the following cookies:

  * Strictly necessary cookies. These are cookies that are required for the operation of our website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our website.
  * Analytical/performance cookies. They allow us to recognise you whenever you visit the website (this speeds up your access to the website as you do not have to log in each time) and to carry out research and statistical analysis to help improve our content, products and services and to help us better understand our visitor and/or customer requirements and interests.
  * Functionality cookies. These are used to recognise you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalise our content for you, for example, your choice of language or region.
  * Targeting cookies. These cookies record your visit to our website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant and personalised to your interests.

The information we obtain from our use of cookies will not usually contain your personal data. Although we may obtain information about your computer or other electronic device such as your IP address, your browser and/or other internet log information, this will not usually identify you personally. In certain circumstances we may collect personal information about you, but only where you voluntarily provide it (e.g. by completing an online form).

In most cases we will need your consent in order to use cookies on this website. The exception is where the cookie is essential in order for us to provide you with a service you have requested.

## Consent

There is a notice on our home page which describes how we use cookies and which also provides a link to our website privacy policy. If you use this website after this notification has been displayed to you, we will assume that you consent to our use of cookies for the purposes described in this website cookie policy and our website privacy policy.

## Third-party cookies

We work with third party suppliers who may also set cookies on our website. These third party suppliers are responsible for the cookies they set on our website. If you want further information please go to the website for the relevant third party. You will find additional information in the table below and the purposes for which we use them:

**Cookie name** | **Description** | **Purpose of the cookie**  
---|---|---  
Inspectlet | __insp_nv 

__insp_sid

__insp_slim

__insp_targlpt

__insp_targlpu

__insp_uid

| We have engaged Inspectlet to analyse the user behaviour of visitors to this website and provide research information designed to improve the customer experience. Inspectlet’s standard use of cookies and other tracking technologies can enable it to have access to personal information of visitors to this website. Such access to and use of personal information by Inspectlet is governed by Inspectlet’s Privacy Policy (https://www.inspectlet.com/legal#privacy) and handling sensitive data: http://www.inspectlet.com/docs… 

By default we do not allow Inspectlet to record any information used to populate any of our forms. Users’ inputted details will not form part of our research.  
  
GoogleAnalytics | _utma 

_utmb

_utmc

_utmz

_gat_UA-86329046-1

_ga

_gid

| Collect information about how visitors use our website. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the website. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have navigated from to our website and the pages visited.   
Salesforce | 00N20000009wTTC 

00N20000009wTTM

00N20000009wTT7

00N20000003JjhG

| Collect information about how visitors use our website. We use the information to compile reports and to help us monitor and improve our marketing campaigns.   
WordPress | langSuggest 

adsId

wordfence_verifiedHuman

bioep_shown_session

cookieaccept

| These are used to recognise users when they visit or return to our website. This enables us to personalise our content for our visitors, for example, their choice of language or region.   
  
## How to turn off cookies

If you do not want to accept cookies, you can change your browser settings so that cookies are not accepted. If you do this, please be aware that you may lose some of the functionality of this website. For further information about cookies and how to disable them please go to the Information Commissioner’s webpage on cookies: [https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/online/cookies/](http://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/online/cookies/).
